So I have a programming assignment for you.
プログラミング課題を 用意しました
I would like you to implement the C++ program for
カルマンフィルター 更新関数のC++プログラムを
the Kalman filter update equations.
実装してください
Let me help you get started.
始めはお手伝いします
So here is the starting code.
これが手始めのコードです
For matrix manipulation, I would like you to use the Eigen library,
行列操作には Eigenライブラリーを使用してください
it has no dependencies and it's really easy to use.
依存性がなく とても使いやすいです
For more details about how to integrate the Eigen library,
Eigenライブラリーの組み込みの 詳細については
take a look at the documentation which I've linked to below.
下記のリンクの ドキュメンテーションを見てください
In order to perform matrix operations, I have to include the Eigen/Dense header.
行列操作を実行するためには Eigen/Denseヘッダーを含める必要があります
Additionally, all classes and functions defined in
また このヘッダーで 定義されているすべての
this header are in the Eigen name space, so I use it here.
クラスと関数はEigen名前空間にあるので ここでそれを使います
Next, I'm going to show you some examples of working with matrices and
次に メイン関数での 行列とベクターの操作例を
vectors in the main function.
示します
You'll be able to run this examples in the code editor after this video.
この例はこのビデオの コードエディターで実行できます
You can create a vertical vector of two elements with a common like this.
このように共通点のある 2つの要素の垂直ベクターを作成できます
And if the vector size was previously specified, you can use
またベクターサイズが 以前に指定されている場合は
the so-called comma initializer to set all the coefficients to some values.
いわゆるコンマ初期化子を使用して すべての係数を何らかの値に設定できます
And you can use the cout comment to print out the vector,
またcoutコメントを使用して ベクターを出力できます
as you will see here.
こんな風に
The matrices can be created in the same way.
同じ方法で 行列を作成できます
For example, this is an initialization
たとえば これは(2,2)行列を
of a (2,2) matrix with the values 1, 2, 3, and 4.
値1 2 3 4で 初期化しています
I print it here, and this is my output.
これをプリントすると これが出力です
You can use the same comma initializer, or
同じコンマ初期化子を使用するか または
you can set each matrix value explicitly, like this.
各行列の値を このように明示的に設定することができます
Also you can compute the transpose of a matrix with the transpose method.
転置メソッドで行列の転置を 計算することもできます
And here is how you can get the matrix inverse.
そしてこれが 行列を逆転する方法です
And you can multiply matrices and vectors,
また行列とベクターを 乗算できます
as you do with normal variables, as you can see here.
普通の変数と同じように このように
Now, that you've seen how to use the Eigen library,
Eigenライブラリーの 使い方を見たので
let's take a look at the code that you'll be working with in this quiz.
このクイズで扱う コードを見てみましょう
At the top of 'tracking_1D.cpp', I declared all the Kalman filter variables here.
トラッキングの最初の1D CPPで すべての共通フィルター変数を宣言しました
Jumping down into the main function, for our 1D motion case,
メイン関数までジャンプして 1Dモーションケースについて
I initialize them with the same values as in the previous lesson.
前のレッスンと同じ値で 初期化します
You can't see them all right now, but I promise they are there.
全部は見えませんが まちがいなく ここにあります
And here is my mostly empty filter function, where I iterate
そしてフィルタという名前の 空の関数を用意しています
over my list of measurements and where I want you to add your code.
ここで最小限の測定を繰り返しています そしてここにあなたのコードを追加してください
Concretely, I want you to implement the measurement update and the prediction
具体的には 測定の更新と予測ステップを
steps inside the loop, given all the matrices initialized before.
ループの内側に実装してください 以前に初期化した行列をすべて指定して
If you need some help, take a look back at the filter implementation you made
困ったときは、セバスチャンのレッスンで 行ったフィルターリング実装を
in Sebastian's lesson.
見直してください
After this video, you can find the link to the same programming quiz in Python.
このビデオの後 Pythonでの同じ プログラミング問題へのリンクがあります
Good luck.
頑張ってください